All your altcoins, most of them are
probably not going to go up in price
again. I think ETH is very hated. People
don't like it. And so if I want to bet
on something, the change in the cycle, I
think you could outperform. Could you
briefly share your inspiration and how
you came up with per? Uh, basically, do
you trade perspect
250,000 by the end of the year? I don't
think it's politically palable to buy
money. Our banker couldn't explain why
Taiwanese dollar jumped 10% in a couple
days compared to USD. Taiwan life
insurers are probably some of the
richest institutions in the world.
They've been investing abroad and
essentially Taiwan is obviously you know
a big global manufacturing hub
semiconductors and all that but the
government and the central bank has a
policy of keeping the Taiwan dollar very
very weak and so to do that they have to
create Taiwan dollar local liquidity
which obviously is the reason why
apartments are so expensive in Taipei
and other cities. Who has the best party
in Asia?
That's the right answer. All right,
guys.
Oh, that's like part. You create all
this money and you can spend on anything
you want.
They already got
script. Privileged to have Arthur Hayes
on the show, CIO of Maelstrom,
co-founder of BitMEX, inventor of
perpetual futures, a widely used
instrument all across exchanges in the
world. Arthur, it's great to see you.
Thanks for having me. Barney Chang is my
uh co-host for uh the show. Barney, why
don't you take it away? I'm so excited
to have you here. Oh my goodness. Okay,
first question is about Taiwanese
dollar. Um our banker couldn't explain
why Taiwanese dollar jumped 10% in a
couple days um compared to USD. Can you
um Yeah. So, it's quite interesting. I
won't go too deep into it but
essentially there were some interesting
articles written by in the FT by I think
Brad Setszer and another economist
basically documenting how Taiwan
lifeurers are probably some of the
richest institution in the world who've
been investing abroad and and
essentially Taiwan is obviously you know
big global manufacturing hub
semiconductors and all that but the
government and the central bank has a
policy of keeping the Taiwan dollar very
very weak and So to do that they have to
create Taiwan dollar local liquidity
which obviously is the reason why
apartments is so expensive in Taipei and
other cities and they accumulate dollars
but they don't want to look bad like
currency manipulators to the United
States government. So they take all
these dollars and they funnel them to
the the Taiwanese lifeurers and then
these life insurers go and they buy
bonds and enter in all sorts of
structured derivatives with large banks.
Um essentially they have a lot of US
treasury bond exposure and also a lot of
hedge funds like to fund themselves in
Taiwan dollar because of this persistent
weakness that is encouraged by the
government and then they engage in
massive carry trades. And so what
happened in the first week of May is
that there is this fear that oh my god
what if the Taiwanese lifers start going
out of the treasury market taking that
money and repatriating into the Taiwan
dollar. And basically a lot of these
hedge funds exited their carrier trades
and got stopped out. And that's why you
saw the 6 or 7% move in the Taiwan
dollar. And I think that the authorities
didn't want to step in and create more
money in Taiwan to basically reverse
those flows because they wanted to show
to the Trump team when they're
negotiating that, hey, we're not about
to let our currency continue to weaken.
We we accept that we're going to have to
allow the Taiwan dollar to strengthen.
And I think that's why you had this sort
of massive move in the Taiwan dollar.
and I expect it to continue to
strengthen over time. Do you think
that's going to happen in other Asian
countries? Yes. And it already started.
You saw it in South Korea. You see it to
some extent in Singapore, Malaysia, and
Thailand. Um any of these countries that
were in these persistent programs of
currency weakness, accumulation of
dollars in the reserve account,
investing abroad, that money is coming
back. And you said um there is capital
control in US coming. Yes. On foreign um
investment ownership. So, I think
they're going to start by taking away
the withholding tax exemption. Um,
there's already talk of that happening
where, you know, foreigners don't pay
the 30% tax that Americans do, getting
interest on their their bonds. So,
they're going to remove that. So, it's
going to make mean that, hey, maybe this
Treasury bond isn't so attractive and
I'll I'm not going to own that. I'll own
something else. So, I think that's going
to start happening. Does that mean a
market crash? No, because they'll print
the money to make sure that all the
foreigners who leave, they'll replace
that with printed money. Well, actually
on that note, in early April you saw uh
bonds go down with stocks, Bitcoin uh
yield went down as well, yield went up.
So I wonder if um capital controls are
going to be, you know, recreate that
kind of scenario where all asset classes
uh go down slightly and uh basically
we'll have less liquidity in the US
system. I think that'll be rolled in
slowly over time and so you're not going
to see this knee-jerk reaction. And I
think the Trump administration learned
that these sorts of massive sort of
changes are going to create outcomes
that they don't like, which is
heightened bond market volatility,
things going the wrong way. And so if
capital controls are going to be phased
in over time, they know that they need
to replace that buying, either it's the
Fed, it's the Treasury, it's the banking
system, it's some other private sector
actor that has allowed to create credit
very cheaply and therefore replace these
foreigners who will be forced to sell
these assets. stocks have recorrelated
with the tang yield and so has Bitcoin.
Do you see that correlation holding
between these three classes? No, I think
that there will be some, you know,
riskoff events and we'll see bond market
volatility heightened. I think Bitcoin
will assert itself as a a hedge against
this. You once said buy everything chai
America lives and then you talk about
their breakup.
Are they getting married or are they
breaking up? I think they're going to
break up over time, but it's not going
to be as quick as some people think,
which is could be decades. Oh, I see.
Um, okay. So, tell me more about what
happens if foreign money leaves like to
the global system. What does that look
like? Well, if foreign money went into
the US because the US markets have been
the the best performing, whether it's
stocks, bonds, or or real estate. And if
that money is leaving and it's going to
go back into their local markets, then
the US markets don't do so well. And
maybe it's better to own Taiwanese
stocks or Indonesian stocks or Taiwanese
uh Thai Thai stocks or you know all
these other emerging market countries
who are basically going to say okay
we're going to we're forced to
repatriate this money back on shore. Our
currencies appreciate our consumer gets
wealthier because now they can purchase
more things and maybe people want to
build business domestically to service
that economy. And the stable coin bill
is that a way to force issuers to buy
more tea bills? I don't think so. I
think it's a way to allow banks to
engage in the same sort of trade that
Tether does. And so if I'm a bank and
now I can create my own stable coin, I
essentially can onboard deposits at zero
cost and then if they remove the
supplemental leverage ratio exemption, I
can buy a T bill and I get to capture
100% of that income. Um I heard this um
argument from one of the exchange
owners. He said um other countries
should not really try that hard anymore
because US has already won this crypto
or Bitcoin war because the underlying um
asset or how people purchase Bitcoin is
with USDT and that's USD. Uh I mean I
don't think so. I mean the the biggest
revenue generating market in the world
for crypto is Korean traders. So I
I'm not exactly sure America's won
anything. It's just another player in
the game.
Oh my god. I want to ask about Korean
market now. That's the DJ stuff. Have
you been hanging out with Dwan recently?
No, I'm just kidding. Um, all right.
Well, uh, let's move to the Bitcoin
market and then we'll pass it back to
Bonnie for some macro questions. I just,
you know, you talked about this a lot in
the press, but just give us a sense of
the timeline of Bitcoin to a million by
2028. You said, 1250 by end of the year.
Is that still your timeline or have you
Yeah, so I think that we get to 250,000
by the end of the year. It'll be bumpy
along the way obviously, but that's sort
of my end of year price target. And then
a million-doll Bitcoin is what I just
got got off stage talking about how
they're going to print I think in the
realm of 9 trillionish
dollars between now and and that period
of time. And that is, you know, Fanny
and Freddy, the government support
entities that are allowed to create
mortgages in the US, they they will
print 5 trillion. um you will have
probably up to a trillion dollars
purchased by the banking system uh due
to supplemental leverage ratio
exemptions and purchasing things that
the foreigners are selling. And I think
the banks are going to free because they
now don't have to hold all this equity
capital against their treasury book.
Yeah. They can lend more into the real
American economy. And so you're going to
see the amount of loans going to
manufacturing firms increase which is
again that's a increase in credit and
that will make its way into crypto as
well. when the Fed per uh printed a
limited QE back in 2020, all asset
classes went up. It wasn't just Bitcoin.
So, this is good news for Bitcoin, what
you just said, the thesis you laid out,
but it could be good news for everything
else, including stocks, gold, um
potentially even bonds as well. Why
would Bitcoin in particular outperform
everything else in a So, Bitcoin is has
a fixed supply. It's obviously a much
smaller market in terms of market cap.
And so, you have if you have a lot of
things chasing a very small door, then
the price goes up on the margin. And so
that's why Bitcoin has been the best
performing financial asset in the last
15 years. Um, one particular risk that
you've highlighted is the potential for
the next administration to write off the
Bitcoin strategic reserve completely.
Um, if the Democrats win in the next
cycle 2028, and if they cancel the
strategic reserve, would we see a lot of
selling pressure? Maybe. It depends on
how much Bitcoin has accumulated. Um it
depends on you know what the financial
pressures are of of the government right
so I don't I think what they have about
200,000 200,000 bitcoin that they sees
from people the US government that is
and that could be sold obviously if
there's a budget pressure then that's a
v there's variable there's money there
to sell it so they can sell it yeah but
do you see them buying more bitcoin if
they haven't done that yet I don't think
it's politically palable to buy bitcoin
okay and print money I think if you're
going print money. Okay. Either it's tax
cuts or it's build a bridge or build a
hospital. These sort of things that
benefit more people than just a small
sector of people who own Bitcoin. Are
you disappointed that the Bitcoin
Strategic Reserve will not buy more
Bitcoin? Yeah. Why does it not buy more?
Because I heard arguments about them
selling some some gold and buy Bitcoin.
I mean, they could anything is possible,
but I just think it's bad politics. I
think if you're if you create all this
money and you could spend it on anything
you want, surely spending it on buying
Bitcoin is probably not going to be the
best way to get votes.
I think a lot of people here would vote
for that.
That's what she wrote about. They
already got their votes. They don't need
to do that again. Exactly. Oh, I see.
speak.
Hey, I'm about to interview one of the
biggest names in crypto. That's
exciting.
Speech analyzer.
Foreign
B O Na
Pro Elsa premium.
Okay. I want to ask you about altcoin
season. Everyone's asking is it coming
and people are saying hey um this cycle
we have so much garbage
and what is happening now. Well I mean I
think that all your altcoins most of
them are probably not going to go up in
price again because they don't have
product market fit. they don't take any
of the revenue and bring it back to the
token holders and so they're like high
FTV low float VC coins and so
they're not going to do very well and
that's why you've seen like down only
for like you know bar chain maybe mod
whatever launches so these types of
projects these very hyped big round uh
big fundraising round projects going to
be very hard for them to go up in price
because they don't actually have any
clients that spend money but there are
projects that are very good that have
you know product market fit people spend
money that money goes from the protocol
to the token holders and I think the
small subset of products that do that
they're going to do very well pendle
pendle etherfy yeah stuff like that okay
um what about all the VC coins from the
la last cycle they were doing very well
what happened in this cycle I think
again no product market fit and again if
you have a very high valuation that you
need to grow into and you have no
clients actually doing anything on your
chain or your product it's very hard to
generate that in that interest after
you've seen the price go down. And I
think in one of your interviews you said
Bitcoin dominance dominance will hit 70%
and then that is when we might see the
altcoin season coming. Is that I still
think that's going to happen 70%. We're
about 65 now. So still more
outperformance in Bitcoin before we're
not in general. I mean basically you
know Bitcoin dominance is very
predicated on ETH. So if ETH doesn't
move then it's very hard for that ratio
to to really move that that well I think
so I think ETH is very hated people
don't like it and so if I want to bet on
something the change in the cycle I
think ETH could outperform how is
Maelstrom positioning itself in terms of
your allocation priorities right now uh
so most of our portfolio is in Bitcoin
uh a decent slug in ETH and then we have
a lot of uh term sheet projects so
things that are rolling off because of
advisory and investments and things that
we've built on liquid probably etheri
and pendal are probably two uh large
positions. How often do you rotate in
and out of Bitcoin? Um not that often.
Maybe we make one one or two big buying
or selling things every year. Uh because
again it's I don't want to be trading
too much. Yeah. You don't have like a
rebalance mandate? No. No, there's no
mandates. The mandate is outperform
Bitcoin. So, if I can if we can invest
in a new project and it outperforms the
Bitcoin capital that we had to sell to
to invest, that's good. Then we'll buy
more Bitcoin with our profits, right?
Well, we've talked to a lot of Bitcoin
maxis that say that the only way to
outperform Bitcoin is to buy more
Bitcoin. So, in a sense, you know, well,
I mean, I think that's false because you
could obviously
there's a time period over what time
period, right? Salana was at seven and
it went up to 300. If you put all your
money in Salana at $7 and sold it all at
300, you definitely outperformed Bitcoin
over that time period. So, but long
term, I mean, I'm not that smart, you
know, to trade that difference. Okay.
You're the OG in um the exchange game.
And I think a lot of centralized
exchange, they owe you uh gratitude
because I'd say 90% of their revenue is
from per. Um right now, we see Dex's
like Hyperliquid coming out. um the
token is performing great, but there was
this incident of you know the jelly
jelly memecoin and that kind of sparked
the argument of if it if it's actually
decentralized and if you know
centralized exchanges can kill you with
$10 million then is it still safe to use
dexes like that? Well, I think obviously
it's probably less centralized than they
advertised and it seems like, you know,
the people in charge of Hyperlid decided
that they wanted to preserve the buying
power of their HLP versus adhering to
what the market was saying with the uh
liquidations of this jelly token. So, on
one hand, yes, it's not very
decentralized. On the other hand, it's
like, oh well, I guess they really care
about this HLP, which is the back stop
for a lot of the markets, so I feel more
comfortable trading there. Because at
the end of the day, traders don't care
about decentralization. They just want
to they want liquidity and they want to
uh a nice range of products to trade.
So, if Hyper Lipid offers that in a
decentralized way, then fine, let's
trade there. And a lot of um centralized
exchanges, they're heading towards
payment because that's the obvious next
step. How do you see this exchange game
play out in 10 years? I mean, I think
right now it's a perfectly competitive
market. No one has any innovation on
products and where everyone charges the
same fee. And so, it's a it comes down
to marketing. It's very difficult to
stay in the the centralized exchange
game, especially now, especially if
you're in the US and now you're going to
have all the banks offering the same
brokerage services. So, I think it's
going to be very tough for the Coinbases
and Krakens of the world to keep their
profit margins if JP Morgan is not going
to allow their clients to buy Bitcoin.
Speaking of Coinbase, several large
exchanges IPOed in the last couple
weeks. Uh, this sparks a new trend of
crypto becoming mainstream in the S&P
500s while Coinbase is listening to the
S&P 500. So, uh, two-part question. I'll
ask my first part first. Do you think
now all investors investing in the S&P
have to be aware and cognizant of the
fact that they're indirectly exposed to
Bitcoin through any S&P? I don't think
they care, right? A lot of people are
just invested in the index and so they
own an ETF and the ETF owns a lot of
stuff, right? That may or may not agree
with their particular sensibilities, but
they don't care. They just want to be in
the index. With exchanges and see uh
centralized exchanges becoming more
mainstream, do you see a scenario in
which they start siphoning deposits from
the regular person from large financial
institutions like JP Morgans and the and
the Bank of Americas of the world? Uh I
don't think so because these banks have
better distribution networks than than
the crypto companies. So there's no
direct competition in the foreseeable
future. Well, there absolutely is direct
competition, right? So if JP Morgan
offers the ability to buy Bitcoin and
Coinbase does, it's the same Bitcoin
that you're buying, right? So then it
comes down to really just fees. And so
can JP Morgan offer a zero fee trading
because they make so much other money at
other places around the bank versus
Coinbase offering 0% trading? I don't
know. I'm not an expert on the Coinbase
revenue drivers, but I would imagine a
lot of their revenue comes from this
very high margin brokerage business that
they operate. And so if JP Morgan or
Bank of America says it's zero fee
Bitcoin trading, bring your balances
here. Bring your bank deposits here.
Well, then what is Coinbase gonna do?
Well, okay. So JP Morgan chief Jamie
Diamond did say that he's allowing
people to buy Bitcoin. He's not going to
custody yet. If you were to build
another BitMX today, how would you
prepare yourself to compete with Trafi
entering the crypto space next? More
DGEN. I wouldn't be trying to compete in
trading Bitcoin. that is going to be a
loss leading product. Interesting. When
you say go more DJ, what does that mean?
Meme coins. Um, you know, leaning into
the launchpad. I think there's some
there's some things that people can do
to improve sort of the new issue
process. Uh, so I think there's a lot of
more revenue to be earned there than
okay competing on Bitcoin, US dollar
trading, which is going to be again low
margin, highly competitive market. Could
you explain what memecoin is to my mom?
trading culture. Oh, I like that. Okay.
Um I think in your chat with u Anthony
Pmpliano, you talk about how older
generation, they're wealthy and they're
trying to um sell their asset to the new
generation for their retirement. But the
new generation, we are not really buying
and storing things. We're paying for
experiences. How does that play out? Uh
it's gonna be interesting to see how
regulations pay out for crypto, right?
because or any other type of digital
assets because the boomers have stocks
to sell. Does anyone want these stocks?
Maybe to some extent. Do they want that
big suburban house or whatever they have
or apartment in the city? I don't know.
So, I think that's this going to be a
massive issue in terms of if the younger
generation wants to buy things that you
older generation is selling and they
need to sell those things to fund their
retirement, how does that square? Are
they going to increase taxes because the
asset prices of things the boomers own
and went down and they can't afford
their retirement. So then they're going
to tax the young more to to pay for
their retirement and is are the young
going to accept that? I don't know. What
would you guess? I think there's going
to be a lot of intergenerational
conflict. I don't know the outcome of
it.
There could be money printing at the end
of the day, right? Because there's very
easy way for the government to solve
this problem. Everything leads to money
printing basically. That's the solution
of everything. Does money printing lead
to more DGEN activity? Usually, yes.
Because again, if you're if you don't
have a lot of financial assets and
you're watching uh all this inflation
happen all around you, you have to use
more leverage in the little bit of
savings you have to escape. Why is there
less DGEN interest now than in 2021?
What what would you what the interest in
what though? the retail interest in the
altcoins and actually some people track
also crypto channel volume viewership
volume is significantly lower now than
four years ago despite the fact that
Bitcoin and many other things have
reached new highs again I think a lot of
these coins have not performed very well
they were priced wrong they were priced
too expensive and then the their their
actual fundamentals when you actually
said okay you launched the hype is over
okay where are the clients where's
revenue oh we don't have any uh but this
thing is a 5 billion enough TV. Well,
how do you can't 10x that? It's just
hard. You go from 5 to 50. It's easy to
10x 100 to 1 billion in terms of on the
marginal price basis. So, I think it's
just the price is too expensive. Is it
too farfetched to say that Bitcoin has
become an institutional instrument now
and the retail crowd is just no longer
interested in that? No, I'm sure there's
lots of retail interest in Bitcoin. It's
been well performing and it's the
easiest one to understand. Okay.
Go ahead. Um, you spent a lot of time in
Asia and I want to know what you learn
from Asia when it comes to money and
investment that is pretty much different
from the US. Uh, don't trust the
government. I don't think any Asians
actually trust their government and so
they're a lot a lot more skeptical of
things and they save in different ways.
Obviously, gold is big in Asia, property
investment, those sorts of things. But I
think the mentality is just different.
Is it more deent or is it more
conservative? It depends on who you're
asking. I think it's a whole range of
people. Why is Korea trading so much?
Uh, so very high internet penetration,
very high gaming culture, very
ethnically homogeneous,
and um very low opportunity for most
individuals to escape, you know, a
shitty life. You know, they very highly
educated, but there's no jobs and make
any real money in Korea. And so either
they're trading stocks or or now they're
they're trading crypto. Everyone's
trying to get ahead um because it's just
such a brutal rat race in in Korea. Who
has the best party in Asia? The best
part is in Asia. Oo, I haven't been to
Taiwan in a while. I have to say Taipei.
That's the right answer, man. Well, he's
speaking to two Taiwanese people.
There's only one right answer.
And he actually goes to the local local
party like those that I haven't been to.
My god. Okay. Well, I guess we both
learned something from Arthur today. Um,
I'm going to switch it back to markets
for just uh one more question here. Um,
open interest in Bitcoin futures reached
unprecedented levels recently. I think
it was uh checking my notes 89 $80
billion on May 22nd, $15 billion
increase in just 5 days. It's
highlighting just unprecedented
leverage. Um, what does this signal to
you? Just more interest in in the space,
right? Obviously, we rallied up towards
all-time high and obviously people are
opening more leverage positions thinking
that we're going to run, you know, past
110 much higher quickly. So, I think
that is in your past experience uh
running BitMEX uh whenever open interest
in future spikes uh what tends to happen
next. I think we want to look for basis
expanding. So, what's that premium of of
Bitcoin versus other things? And so, I
don't think it's any anything crazy.
It's like 10% or something, right? Were
there any indicators on BitMX in
particular that signaled huge market
movement afterward that were pretty
consistent, you think? No, I haven't
identified any, but I haven't I didn't
look that closely. So, cool. Could you
briefly share your inspiration and how
you came up with per? Uh, basically me
and my co-founders answered all support
tickets and our clients didn't
understand futures contracts. They
didn't understand why the price was
different than spot. They didn't
understand why they expired and so we
thought, can we create a product that
has no expiry but highly leveraged? And
so this was the impetus to create the
perpetual swap. And so we tinkered
around with it until we found the
product that everyone is familiar with
and launched it in May 2016. Most people
hated it for a while, but then over time
they started trading it because this
solved a problem for us because it was
very timeconuming for us to answer the
same question over and over again. And
um do you trade herbs? No. Reason? I
don't usually trade on leverage. Uh if I
buy anything, I buy it on a spot basis.
And um do you encourage people to I
encourage people who have the time to
spend to be good at their craft to trade
using leverage? If you don't have the
time and you don't have the patience,
then don't use leverage. Okay. So let's
say if I were to um use PERS, what is
the first thing I should think of? Is it
risk? My position size, what is it? I
have a goal. What is their goal? Like I
I want to make this percentage and
what's your downside? What's your
upside? When do you cut? When do you
add? like have a plan before you start
trading because then the emotions take
over and then you know you'll make a
mistake.
Uh final question for me what's next for
Melstrom? Any new plans? Any new
expansion? Any new projects? So we're
actually launching a a buyout business.
So we are raising investor capital and
buying specific crypto businesses with a
nod to uh revamp management you know
focus on adding different revenue lines
and then taking these companies public
probably via a spa in the United States.
So, we've identified uh one target
that's which we're going to be going out
with shortly to to raise money and
hopefully uh really increase the the
bottom line of this business. Can you
give us more detail right now?
Absolutely. I can't yet, but it'll be
very clear serly when we sign this deal.
Well, without giving too much detail,
what types of businesses and what kind
of operations are you interested in? So,
we're interested in businesses that make
um are highly cash flow positive. So the
one that we're looking at now makes a
very good amount of money, high high
cash flow, positivity, and we're getting
it at a very decent price relative to
Okay. So it wouldn't be um like an angel
investing kind of thing. No, this is not
an angel investing thing. Um how do you
personally pick altcoin? What do you
look at? Uh narrative and now it's all
about cash flow. So do you generate a
lot of cash flows? Is there a way for me
as the investor to get paid by
supporting you by owning your your coin
and not the valuation?
Well, I mean early early stage stuff
were very we have caps on how much we'll
pay. Um very specific. Um but liquid
stuff it's really about cash flows for
me. Don't you feel narrative change too
quickly? It's very hard to catch on. Um
it does, but if you pay the right price,
it doesn't matter. If you pay low enough
price, if it launches, most likely
you'll make money. But if you pay the
high price when you're chasing the
narrative and trying to be in every
single big deal, then that's when you
lose money. What is your favorite Asian
food? Oh, my favorite Asian food.
I probably have to say prawn me. Oh,
what is it? Prawn me. Prawn me. Oh,
okay. Yeah. Yeah. The Vietnamese uh
Singaporean. Yeah. Yeah. Oh, Singapore.
Okay. Yeah. I I need to catch up on my
Southeast Asian food. David, on that
note, let's go eat some Asian food
together sometime. Thank you guys. That
was a lot of fun. Thank you.